Net Promoter Score is a measurement of customer loyalty.
Net Promoter Score （中文：净推荐值）是衡量用户忠诚度的指标
A company's Net Promoter Score or NPS for short,
通过一个标准简单问题来
is measured in a survey that asks one simple question,
评估一家公司的净推荐值 简称 NPS
"How likely is it that you would recommend our company to a friend or colleague?"
“你有多大可能把我们（或这个产品/服务/品牌）推荐给朋友或同事？”
Following the question is a consistent scale with a range
这个问题的选项是一个标准打分范围 要求用户 从 0-10 打分
from 0-10,0 being not an unlikely,
0 分代表完全没有可能推荐
5 being neutral, and 10 being extremely likely.
5 分代表中立态度  10 分代表极有可能推荐
This simple question provides fantastic insight into customer loyalty,
这个问题虽然简单 但是提供了客户忠诚度的最可靠的判断
and eliminates long and complicated surveys that most people ignore.
同时取代了那些人们通常都选择忽略的很长又复杂的问卷调查
Now this idea was introduced by Fred Reichheld in 2003,
NPS 概念由 Fred Reichheld 于 2003 年
through a Harvard Business Review article.
在哈佛大学商业评论的文章中首次提到
Reichheld invested two years into research,
Reichheld 花了两年时间研究
linking survey responses with actual customer behavior,
将问卷回答与实际的客户行为关联在一起
and the results revealed the true value of NPS.
结果反映了 NPS 的真实价值
This one question about a customer's willingness to
这个问题 - 用户将你的产品或服务推荐
recommend your product or service reveals their true loyalty.
给其他人的意愿反映了他们真实的忠诚度
Based on the score a customer indicates,
根据用户回答的分值
they fall into one of three groups: promoter, passive, or detractor.
可以将用户分成三类：推荐者 被动者 贬损者
A promoter would score 9 or 10.
推荐者的分值一般在 9 或 10 分
There are huge fans of the product of
他们是你的产品或服务的忠实粉丝
the service and they go out of their way to advocate for it.
愿意花大力气来向别人推荐你的产品
Promoters put their own reputation on the line.
推荐者压上了他们自己的信誉度
A responsive 7 or 8 makes that customer passive.
如果分值是 7 或者 8 就是被动者
This person probably liked what you had to offer,
被动者对你的产品有好感
but there was no wow factor.
但是仅限于此 并没有惊艳到他们
They may have had a few issues or didn't see much value over the competition.
他们可能有一些小问题 或者并没有觉得你的产品或者服务比竞争对手的好很多
A passive customer isn't likely to steer others away from your company,
被动者不会阻止别人使用你的产品或服务
but they're not going to recommend it,
但他们也不会向其他人推荐
and finally anyone answering with a score of 6 or below, becomes a detractor,
最后 分值为 6 分以及 6 分以下的用户 是贬损者
and a detractor will take any chance they can get to
贬损者会利用他们可以利用的各种机会
push people away from your product or service.
阻止别人使用你的产品或服务
Detractors are often more vocal than promoters,
贬损者通常比推荐者更愿意说出他们的想法
because their level of dissatisfaction is incredibly high.
因为他们真的极其不满意
The ratings are then used to develop one numerical score,
这些分值最终将变成一个数值
and this metric allows companies to quantify how
NPS 数值可以让一个公司定量分析如果对产品或服务做出了某些改变
changes to a product or service impact the customer experience over time.
对客户体验产生了这样的影响
Now, a score of greater than 50 is pretty good.
基本上 NPS 大于 50% 就很不错了
But you can do some research on NPS by brand or
你可以根据品牌或者行业在看它们的 NPS 值
industry and see how it pans out in your specific market.
然后看看在你的特定目标市场的情况
The biggest takeaway here,
最重要的是
is that you need to be working to measure this to
你需要通过衡量 NPS 来判断
identify if you're securing loyal customers.
你是否有忠实的用户
Customer loyalty is one of the most important drivers of growth,
用户忠诚度是驱动增长的最重要因素之一
so take some time to consider the advantage of evaluating your NPS.
所以花点时间想想 衡量 NPS 能带来多少好处
You can start by surveying
刚开始的时候 可以选定
a statistically valid sample of
具有统计学意义的用户数量
your customers with that question we talked about earlier,
然后问他们 NPS 问题
"How likely is it that you would recommend our company to a friend or colleague?"
"你有多大可能把我们（或这个产品/服务/品牌）推荐给朋友或同事？"
Introduce that scale from 0-10,
给他们介绍打分范围 0-10
along with the key for what those values correspond to,
以及各个分数代表的意义
and then collect the results.
最后收集结果
It's really important that you resist the urge to add any additional survey questions.
你必须要抵制住自己想要加问题的冲动 这非常重要
You only need that one question to determine their status.
你只要问这一个问题来判断他们的忠诚度
From there, you calculate your score.
接下来 就可以计算比分了
You take the percentage of customers who responded with nine or
将分值为 9 或者 10 的客户的比例
10 and subtract the percentage who respond with 0 through 6.
减去 分值为 0-6 的客户的比例
In other words, subtract the percentage of detractors
也就是说 将推荐者的比例减去
from the percentage of promoters to arrive at your Net Promoter Score.
贬损者的比例 这是你的 NPS
Don't be surprised if the score is lower than you might expect.
如果 NPS 值比预期低 不用太惊讶
The median Net Promoter Score of more than 400 companies
400 多家公司 跨 28 个行业的 NPS 中位数
across 28 industries was just 16.
仅仅是 16 而已
You might also consider measuring your Net Promoter Score across specific regions,
你也可以基于特定地区、产品或者客户细分来衡量 NPS
But what really counts is how your company compares with direct competitors.
但是真正重要的是 你要与你的直接竞争对手比较 NPS
Now, there's a lot of online resources that you can use to survey these customers.
网络上有很多资源 可以用来展开用户调查
Just run a Google search for NPS survey tools and evaluate the options,
可以用 Google 搜索 NPS 调查工具 然后筛选下
to see what fits your needs.
看看哪个工具能符合你的需求